Hey, so this is a video about uh Blender
emulators and ripping stuff out of PS2
games. Okay, so I discovered this thing
called a RPCS uh to 3D screenshot tool,
a snapshot. Um it's really freaking
handy. It's amazing. And I want to show
you you how to get it. Okay, so uh let's
do it. So, basically what you want to do
is
go to this link I sent you, and I'm
going to put it in the description. You
can find it there. Okay? Um, and
download the this is a mod of the PS2
emulator PCSX2.
Okay? So, once you get that set up, um,
you should see that you should have it
in your documents folder once you get it
set up. and we'll be going to the snap
folder later. So, keep an eye on it.
Okay.
So, once you do that, you want to boot
up your emulator and pick the game you
want to do. I picked Armor Core Last
Draven. Okay. You need to set your game
uh hold on. You need to set your game a
[__] sake
to software mode. Software rendering.
Okay. Otherwise, it won't work. You got
to do it on software mode. Okay.
So, what you want to do is go ahead and
boot into the game into an area that you
want to take a picture of and take a
picture. So, I'm going to take a picture
of
my fellow right here.
Garage,
my fellow blue J right here.
Going to go to a VR test cuz I want to
get a picture of just him.
So,
I'm going to go ahead and activate debug
mode with this cheat I have in this
game.
So, that way I can turn the camera
around and see my buddy right here.
There we go. Face to face with him.
All right. So, how do you You're
wondering how do we take a 3D
screenshot? Like, how do we do that?
Basically, go to your tools and you
should see save single frame GSD. Click
that and it should save it. All right.
So, let's go ahead and boot up Blender.
Delete all that. So, what you want to do
is import and Wavefront OBJ cuz when you
save it, it's saved as a OBJ file in the
3D scrap uh snapshot folder. So, you go
there, go to your PCXS2 folder, go to
snaps through screenshots, uh, 3D
screenshots, blleh the screenshot 3D,
whatever. Last Raven, you should find it
right on top if you set it to date
modified. Okay, it's the OBJ folder, not
the NTL, the OBJ. All right, make sure,
very important, you click vertex groups.
Keep that on. Okay, that's very
important. And import it. And now,
bam.
There we go. That's the game.
Now, you see this guy's fairly squished.
This game, I find that the scaling
modifier for it is uh pretty simple.
It's SZ4,
Sx3,
but you're going to have to scale it
depending on how the game works and how
the camera angle is and etc, etc. So,
just get it to look nice essentially.
But with this game, where the camera is
at, this is pretty much fine because it
takes a screenshot of where the camera
is. That's why it doesn't have anything
behind it. Um, if you want to do
everything around it, uh, you're going
to have to find a way to get out of
bounds or cheat the game and, uh, get
everything you need. So, now I'm going
to click on my AC. You see, I can't
click on it. That's cuz it's everything.
This whole thing is one giant mesh.
Okay, there's a command to fix that. All
right.
It's really dang handy and it's helped
me a ton.
I'll probably put it in the description.
I should
um this one. Separate selection by
material.
It's this command right here. This
command is really, really helpful. Make
sure you have this selected and then
click play.
Bam. Now everything's its own model.
Okay. So, I can click this. I can click
this, this, this, this, this, all that.
It's It's separated by material. Okay.
So, I'm going to delete the stuff I
don't want right now because I just want
the AC.
And then I'm going to delete everything
else like that. Bam.
This guy right there.
All right. I'm going to go ahead and
line him up
there. And now you see there's some
texture issues right here. That's cuz
this game specifically does have issues
with this. So, I figured out how to fix
it. Okay. Um, whenever you rip these
models, you will get two vertex groups
for everything. Okay. And they will be
in the data tab once you click an item.
They will be normal and cold. Generally,
you want to delete the cold ones. Uh, if
it's like super simple. So, I'll give
you an example. See this core? It has
some issues right here, right there. And
the little fin right there for the
exceed orbit is all messed up. So what I
want to do, go to edit mode. Once I
click it, go to select and delete like
this. Bam.
Yeah, it's fixed. Like that.
Basically,
if you if you can bulk do it
without ruining your model, that's how
you want to do it. Okay. There is a
chance though that it will mess with
your model um whenever you do this. So
just keep an eye out whenever you do
this stuff and make sure
that when you do it
you don't delete anything important.
See right now I'm not seeing any issues.
I don't see through the model or
anything. It's fine.
Let's do the legs.
Select
vertices
and the legs. Same fine. Cool. Now, you
might be thinking, what if I want to rip
a whole map? You can do that. You saw me
do rip part of the map right there.
However, it will also have these art it
will be guaranteed to have these
artifacting issues uh from what I've
experienced with ripping from AC games.
So, I uh it depends on where you you do
it. If you do cold, um it'll get
everything that was not on the screen.
So, um there's this menu in Armor Cord
Nexus, the garage. If you take a 3D
screenshot in there and then you delete
the cold ones, it'll delete everything
generally that is off the screen. Like,
uh whenever you're Yeah. When you're in
the garage, you won't be able to. It's
all the stuff in camera
and the cold is essentially everything
outside of the camera. It's basically
guessing. Uh it's it's rendering the
stuff that the PS2 isn't. Um whereas the
normal is rendering the PS2 stuff. So
that's generally how I think about that.
Um
so go ahead and fix this rifle up real
quick.
Bam.
And bam.
So,
this is a good project and you generally
want to save it and all that. Um,
but but but
uh you might be like, "Oh, I I [__] up
and my undo isn't too much." Uh, don't
forget to go to your preferences,
save and load, and set your thing up to
where the [__] is it? Memory limits
right here. Undo steps. Set that to as
far as you can. Um, that's very
important. I I I figured that out, my
experience, so don't forget that. But
yeah, that's generally how this works.
Um, this is a very simple overview. It
could go more in depth, but there's I'm
generally just doing a simple one. Um,
and yeah, uh, I hope whoever sees this,
you have a good day and get to ripping,
ripper. Uh, make make me proud.